hi with all the recent videos I've done
on switchboards I thought I'd do my lab
here my lab switchboard I don't think
I've ever done a video showing my lab
switchboard well here it is it's in the
distribution board it's literally inside
my lab rate my poster on the front I
think it's very appropriate and I've got
other posters here hav't hung that one
that's a signed Buzz Aldren original
print and this is a limited edition
signed Drew stren uh Back to the Future
poster look at this a beautiful limited
edition print that one oh it's just
gorgeous anyway let's go inside the
panel shall we so this is a very typical
box uh you'll find inside any commercial
office unit here in Sydney I assume it's
same all around Australia leave it in
the comments it's inside because well
you need control over you know if your
computer uh blows a circuit or something
you need to be able to reset it you
don't want to have to go down to the
main distribution board which is
actually on this level um here so uh
that's in a uh its own room but anyway
let's open it up there you go um not a
huge amount of circuits inside this
thing okay what we've got here is a uh
emergency lighting control cuz I've got
like an exit light it's just a
requirement even though there's only one
door here you know I need an exit light
and they do come around and test it
every uh 12 months they physically put
it into test mode here and it then it
switches over to there's a battery in
the light so even in the power of the
whole building fails all of the uh exit
lights will still operate so yeah that's
part of your uh requirement to keep your
uh you know your lease or whatever even
though I own this place um they still
have to it's part of the strata
requirements that they have to come
around and test this anyway uh we've got
the main isolator here these are a
Merlin uh brand I haven't se seen a
Merlin in residential but I don't know
maybe leave it in the comments down
below how do you rate uh melin so I've
obviously got three phases coming in
here because uh there's three phases
here um and then we've got a airon
breaker we've got a light breaker
neither of those are um rcd have an
earth leakage or a residual current
device uh in them but the uh power to
the near wall here so basically it's
split into two the near wall is the one
uh here and then we've got power in
firewall they do have um build-in rcds
in them and when I leased my office out
and they redid the cubicle here um they
added a whole bunch of power points um
along the middle wall along the cubicle
wall so they had an extra Schneider one
added here and um yeah it's rcd
protected as well they're all 20 amp
jobes hot water CU there's an instant
hot water thing in the kitchen cabinet
here I don't use it cuz I don't drink
tea or coffee so have no no use for the
hot water and uh the kitchen lights here
um has an old school residual current
device so so that is an older School uh
Double D slot one whereas now they're
all like integrated into like a single
uh slot here and uh and then the one for
the um exit light up there of course so
yeah not many but I only have like a
small 50 me office here all right take
out the self tappers here and let's have
a squiz inside and this will just pop
off like that taada look at that easy
peasy lemon squeezy so up the top you
can see that we got a DIN rail there
that's specifically there for that exit
light uh timer thing and you can see the
orange conduit coming in there I don't
know why there's an extra um cable going
up there like a white like a power point
cable going up through the entry um
anyway on the left hand side of course
there's all the outlet wires going to
the Powerpoints and lights and uh
whatever else they go to so I won't
bother removing that panel but obviously
uh you know the wi are loomed uh behind
there and aha this is interesting we do
actually have three different phases
here no I'm not going to touch it um
they are like plastic coated on the
outside of those metal bars and you can
see that the red one goes into this
phase here the white one in the middle
goes to this phase and the blue one goes
to this phase here so um yes they do
actually and you can see how they just
spread them across here so yes they
inside each individual unit here in the
uh commercial office building they do
seem to split the phase so they're uh
doing this at the individual unit level
rather than relying on uh the original
Builders to uh like do it like one unit
on one phase another unit on another
phase and stuff like that so yeah it's
it's more better um to do it at the
individual office level so then you can
guarantee like if one office is taking a
ton of power you don't want that coming
uh from one phase uh and and another
office is doing you know hardly anything
at all then yeah um it's better to share
it at the individual office uh level so
that's what they've done here so that's
really cool so I hadn't actually
remembered that from uh the last time I
can't remember the last time I poked in
here anyway uh there some vertical din
rails behind here uh some very large uh
spaces like a 10 cm or something off the
rear wall there we've got our neutral uh
block over here and we've got our Earth
block uh over here apart from that it's
pretty basic I mean here's our main
neutral link coming in over here here's
our main Earth link you can tell by the
diameter of the cables there so whoa
hang on having just gone through that
whole phase explanation here um you'll
notice that there's a blue wire and a
white wire that's two of the phases and
the red other red wire coming in here so
it is three phases coming in but you can
see that the three-phase switch in here
is just linked um to the one phase that
red phase and I can I can't show you
here but if I poke my head up here and
have a look the white phase and the blue
phase are just um terminated well
they're not terminated they're just
insulated um flapping around in the
breeze behind there so this actually is
only a single phase um office unit even
though they went to all the trouble to
install the three different phase bus
bars here and everything and they just
couldn't be asked to wire up the uh blue
and the white into all all they had to
do was wire the blue and white into blue
into here and white into here or what
white into here and blue into here and
and Bob's your uncle they didn't do that
it's all off the one phase so I I have
not touched it since I've been here no
electrician has touched it since I've
been here so I don't know why they've
done that they went to all that effort
and they yet only put it on one phase so
I don't know if you got any clue why
that would happen if you're into your
commercial electrics at all I know
there's lots of electricians who watch
uh the evev blogs so if you do any
commercial work um tell us why they
would have done that um it just doesn't
seem to make sense they went all the
effort to do the three-phase stuff yet
they just paired off one phase weird huh
so anyway hope you found that
interesting if you did please give it a
big thumbs up and as always discuss down
below and check out the eev blog. store
catch you next time
[Music]